Rohit Kakani

Senior Inside Sales Manager

Contact

Address

Hyderabad, India 500081

Phone

9701486451

E-mail

rohitkakani95@gmail.com

Skills

Relationship building skills

Advanced

Recruitment

Advanced

Employee training

Advanced

Communications management

Advanced

Pricing structures

Advanced

Product branding

Advanced

Languages

English

Advanced

Hindi

Advanced

Telugu

Advanced

Reliable Inside Sales Manager with experience establishing and enforcing service standards and sales goals. Maintained expert product knowledge to address customer needs and optimize business retention. Built, led and motivated teams to excel in competitive environments.

Work History

2023-07 -2023-11

Team Leader

Digital Nest Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad

- Mentored and guided employees to foster proper completion of assigned duties.
- Built strong relationships with customers through positive attitude and attentive response.
- Established open and professional relationships with team members to achieve quick resolutions for various issues.
- Conducted training and mentored team members to promote productivity, accuracy, and commitment to friendly service.
- Monitored team performance and provided constructive feedback to increase productivity and maintain quality standards.
- Communicated KPIs outlined in annual plan to inform employees of expectations and deliverables.
- Assisted in recruitment of new team members, hiring highest qualified to build team of top performers.
- Monitored time and attendance, enforcing compliance with company procedures relating to absenteeism.

2021-01 -2023-04

Senior Inside Sales Manager

Epowerx Learning Technologies Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad

- Secured new accounts by strategically pursuing leads, generating over 1.5 cr in revenue monthly.
- Set and exceeded inside sales goals by establishing ambitious targets and motivating sales representatives.
- Scheduled and led department staff meetings, workshops and functions to encourage and inspire staff.
- Managed 25 sales specialists by coaching on effective sales techniques, monitoring performance and offering helpful feedback.
- Monitored and amplified sales pipeline to maintain flow of potential leads and prospects.
- Trained employees on new technology and sales methods to build highly-knowledgeable and successful team.
- Updated accounts and maintained long-term relationships with clients.
- Surpassed sales goals by 120% annually with implementation of diverse sales tools and strategies.
- Collected Customer data using various research methods to broaden results and optimize marketing strategies.

 Tracked key metrics and developed spreadsheets and data models.

2020-02 -2020-10

Business Development Executive

Jaro Education, Hyderabad

- Developed and executed strategic initiatives to implement key changes and improvements in business development and sales programs.
- Identified and pursued valuable business opportunities to generate new company revenue and improve bottom line profit.
- Communicated directly with customers and partners to build strong business networks and relationships.
- Implemented creative sales training techniques for new and existing staff to increase revenue and overall success.
- Utilized market trends, mission priorities and customer goals to envision, shape and close new opportunities.
- Identified business development challenges and customer concerns for proactive resolution.
- During service generated 85 new customer Accounts in span of 4 Months.

2018-12 -2020-01

Business Development Executive

Funfinity Learning Solutions Pvt.Ltd, Chennai

- Defined and integrated roles, responsibilities and processes for business team and data management organization.
- Identified and pursued valuable business opportunities to generate new company revenue and improve bottom line profit.
- Researched product pricing, ratings and performance and created comparison spreadsheets to evaluate competitors.
- Implemented creative sales training techniques for new and existing staff to increase revenue and overall success.
- Identified business development challenges and customer concerns for proactive resolution.
- Implemented successful approaches to revitalize underperforming product lines and create new profitgenerating enterprises.
- Trained 20 new joiners team during employment.

Education

2016-06 -2018-04 Post Graduate Diploma in Management: Marketing,SupplyChain Management,Digital Marketing

Siva Shivani Institute of Managment - Hyderabad, India

2013-06 -2016-05 **B.Com**(General)

Wesley Degree & PG College - Hyderabad, India

2011-06 -	Intermediate
2013-04	Sri Chaitanya Junior College - Hyder Nagar
2010-06 - 2011-04	Secondary School Certification
	Bhashyam Public School - Hyderabad,India

Accomplishments

- Supervised team of 25 staff members.
- Collaborated with team of 75 in the development of Sales Achievement
- Achieved 1.5Cr by completing Sales Superstar Contest in 2months with accuracy and efficiency.
- Has been promoted Several in a Skill-Lync organization.
- Dec 1st 2021 pre-sales promotion
 Jan 1st 2022- Team lead

 Feb 17th 2022- Domain Manager
 May 15th 2022- Sr. Domain Manager